HASHAN KOGUL YOGENDRAN



CONTACT

+94 778 707 597



hashankogul99uoj@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/hashan-kogul yogendran-698668290



https://github.com/Hashan-Kogul



https://hashan-kogul-portfolio.vercel.app/

EDUCATION

BICT (HONORS) - BACHELOR OF INFORMATION AND COMMUNICATION **TECHNOLOGY**

2020 - Present (Final Year) University of Vavuniya

GRADUATED IN ADVANCED LEVEL (ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY)

2016-2018 Norwood National School

WORK EXPERIENCE

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

NinjaPipe | 2024-Present

After being promoted to Associate Software Engineer, I took on a more comprehensive role encompassing both front-end and back-end development, along with database management system responsibilities. Throughout this journey, I continued to explore and adopt new technologies, refining my skills as a versatile software engineer.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

NinjaPipe | 2023-2024

I was involved in creating a responsive web application for a CRM platform. Throughout the internship, I successfully completed assigned tasks and actively engaged in learning new technologies and concepts relevant to web development.

PROFILE

Forward-thinking software engineer with a strong commitment to drive technological breakthroughs through carefully designed innovative solutions. With a deep-rooted love for all aspects of technology, I'm dedicated to deliver unique software applications that redefine the user experience and push the boundaries of possibilities in the digital realm. I'm continuously ready to learn new technologies and strive for smart solutions that make a meaningful impact.

PROJECTS

TECHE-LEARN

Group Project | 2023

Software engineering is one of our subject module in third year first semester. For that two of us grouped to work under the project. We created an E-learning web application system called TECHE-LEARN using HTML, CSS, Java script, jQuery, Bootstrap, PHP and SQL.

FOODIE-EXPRESS

Group Project | 2023

Advanced web technology is one of our subject module in third year first semester. For that five of us grouped to work under the project. We created an online food ordering web application system called Foodie-Express using HTML, CSS, Java script, jQuery, Bootstrap, PHP and SQL.

MEDXPERT

Development Competition | 2023

AIESEC Moratuwa brought forth an application development drive, during which I collaborated with four peers to successfully construct 'MedXpert' a medical-oriented mobile application, using the Flutter framework.

BASIC WEB APPLICATION PROJECTS

Individual Projects | 2023

- Age Calculator
- Personal Portfolio
- To-Do List App
- File Convertor
- Music Player
- Online Code Editor
- Weather App • Chat Application

SKILLS

WEB DEVELOPMENT

- React JS, React Native
- Web Forms
- Html, CSS
- Tailwind CSS
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Next.js

FRAMEWORKS

- Angular
- Node JS
- PHP
- .NET

DATABASE MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

- XAMPP (primarily includes MySQL)
- SQL Management Studio (for working with SQL Server)
- MongoDB (a NoSQL database)
- GraphQL (a query language for APIs)

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

- C
- C++
- C#
- Java
- Python

VERSION CONTROL AND COLLABORATION TOOLS

- Git and GitHub
- Azure (cloud services platform)
- Jira (project management and issue tracking tool)

SOFT SKILLS

- Time Management
- Adaptability
- Problem-solving
- Leadership

REFERENCES

Mr. V. Senthooran

Senior Lecturer,

Department of ICT,

Faculty of Technological Studies,

University of Vavuniya.

deanfts@vau.ac.lk

+94 24 222 0269

Ms.P.Rukshani

Lecturer (Probationary),

Department of ICT,

Faculty of Technological Studies,

University of Vavuniya.

rukupuvan@gmail.com

+94 77 869 9538

ORGANAIZATIONAL EXPERIENCE

DEVELOPER TEAM LEAD

National Development Team | 2023-Present AIESEC in Sri Lanka

INITIATIVE GROUP VICE PRESIDENT FINANCE & LEGAL

AIESEC in Vavuniya | 2023-Present

G17 UNIVERSITY AMBASSADOR

G17-University Ambassadors Consortium | 2022-2023 University of Vavuniya

STUDENTS' UNION PRESIDENT

Faculty of Technological Studies | 2022-2023 University of Vavuniya

PRESIDENT

TECSO Club | 2022-2023 Faculty of Technological Studies University of Vavuniya

DESIGNING TEAM LEAD

Mozilla Campus Club | 2022-2023 University of Vavuniya

DIRECTOR

National Team Internship Management Committee | 2023-2024 Zero Plastic Movement

MEMBER

AIESEC in Jaffna | 2022-2023

- OGV Team Member
- Partnership Development Team Member
- Developer Team Member (AIESEC in Sri Lanka)

VOLUNTEER

University of Vavuniya | 2022-2023

CERTIFICATIONS

- ASP.NET Core Foundation | Coursera & Microsoft
- Introduction to JavaScript | Solo Learn
- Introduction to C# | Solo Learn & LinkedIn Learning
- HTML Essential Training | LinkedIn Learning
- SQL Programming | LinkedIn Learning & NASBA & Solo Learn
- Succeeding in Web Development: Full Stack and Front End | LinkedIn Learning
- Figma | Coursera
- Git & GitHub | Udemy
- Programming Fundamentals | LinkedIn Learning
- Java | LinkedIn Learning
- PHP | Solo Learn
- Introduction to IoT | Cisco
- Angular | Solo Learn